# Batbayar Sukhbaatar

2 Hillview Rise, Singapore, 667978 +65-91444519 | batbayar.sukhbaatar@gmail.com

Website | Linkedin | Github | Stackoverflow

## **Personal statement**

I am working as a fullstack developer for eight years. I experience different types of technologies every day, which makes me more passionate about fullstack. It feels like I am having a wide range of options that I could develop myself.

## **Core skills**

- Various programming languages experience. Ruby, Javascript, Typescript, SQL, Golang, Java, PHP...
- Production level experience in different Databases. MySQL, PostgreSQL, Firestore, MongoDB
- Frameworks, libraries such as Ruby on Rails, React, Vuejs, Angular, Vert.x, Firebase,
  Codeigniter, Heroku
- Cloud environment, server, and tools experience: AWS, Bash, Terraform
- Have been working on different types of platforms, systems such as advertisement, crowdsourcing, web scraping, data mining, and several internal platforms, dashboards
- Experience in development approaches like an agile, and waterfall

# **Employment history**

## Senior Fullstack Developer - Songo

*Remote (2018.06 - Present)* 

I am encountering exciting experiences while working on this project. Work with experienced people, participate in the decision-making process, and work in every part of the development backend, frontend, developer experience, deployment, infra management.

#### **Duties**

- Designed backend rest api, authentication system and have done it with minimal workforce using Postgresql, Postgrest, Vert.x.
- I have designed and implemented continuous deployment with gitlab for backend and frontend projects. As a result, the company securely kept sensitive data, and deployment time and failure reduced drastically.
- In the frontend development, actively work on new challenges and improvement on single page application built with Vue.
- Shifted frontend project hosting from EC2 instance to S3 + Cloudfront, and it reduced hosting costs while increased availability.

#### Senior Fullstack Engineer - Grab

Singapore (2017.12 - Present)

It is an excellent opportunity to take a look at a fast-growing company and learning a lot from talented people in coding and non-coding skills.

#### **Duties**

- Every day, I work with well structured, dedicated teams to deliver a reliable code.
- Work following an agile development cycle, and it was interesting to see the inequality from the waterfall method.

- Participated in immersion programs to understand the requests and pain points of users.
  Resolved the raised issues, hence the productivity and experience of users are improved.
- Operate close with SRE to implement new features and upgrade the existing infrastructure.
- Maintained the stability of the projects by completing critical 3rd party integrations, and improving code quality of legacy code.
- Mentored two new members and helped them settle down and understand the workflow.

## Full-stack Developer, Senior - Unimedia

Mongolia (2014.05 - 2017.12)

I had worked on a representative agent of Japan company "Unimedia" in Mongolia for 2.5 years as a fullstack developer then promoted to a senior fullstack developer just before 2017.

#### **Duties**

- Operate jointly with engineering managers to keep AWS based cloud environments scalable, stable, and cost-efficient.
- Installed a rack server in the office to increase development experience. The result was exceptional.
- Implemented internal training for teams that made them prepared to maintain aws infra and act fast on aws related incident.
- Served as a software engineer on a caching system, a crowd-sourcing platform, and a web crawler and made them distributed and reliable.
- Mentored two interns and three new joiners and guided them through the work cycle and environment.

#### **Teacher - Aptech Training Center**

*Mongolia (2012.05 - 2014.04)* 

I was teaching operating systems, computer parts, network, desktop application development, and web application development practically.

#### **Duties**

- Teach various development languages and technologies (HTML, CSS, Javascript, PHP, SQL, C#, Java, etc...) and explain how the computer parts work and examine its components
- Assistant in server administration by managing and maintaining a windows server and network to provide secure, fast, stable studying and working environment.
- Increase overall content quality by modifying and rearranging premade subjects and topics

#### **Education**

#### **Manonmaniam Sundaranar University**

(2010 - 2012)

Bachelor of Computer Science in Computer Applications

#### Aptech Worldwide Mongolia

(2008 - 2011)

Higher Diploma in Software Engineering